

Toronto, Canada moored1@mcmaster.ca +1 (647) 833-1002 linkedin.com/in/davidq4moore unmoore.com

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

Engineering and Management Student with a year of practical work experience focusing on structural design. Structural analysis and design for projects in schools across Toronto requiring familiarity with Ontario and National Building Code and the use of software such as SAP2000, Revit and AutoCAD. Operates efficiently in team environments; often coordinating with multi-disciplinary stakeholders.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE	
Toronto District School Board	Structural Engineering Assistant
May 2018 – August 2018	Prepared structural and architectural drawings using AutoCAD and Revit. Projects include exterior steel stairs, wall replacement, beam replacement, interior steel platforms, wall waterproofing and weeping tiles complete with weld and fastener details.
	Use of SAP 2000 and hand calculations to determine shoring loads, beam selection, capacity of roof structures with snow loads and connections.
	Designed structural guards and prepared shop drawings for awning windows that were stamped and implemented across TDSB schools.
Toronto District School Board May 2017 – August 2017	Structural Engineering Assistant Designed supports for hatches and specified compliance issues and roof access solutions to over 60 schools.
	Reviewed as-built drawings for over 600 TDSB schools to identify potential Siporex and cluster column issues
Toronto District School Board	Environmental Engineering Assistant
May 2016 – August 2016	Reviewed Designated Substance Surveys for over 600 sites for a GIS management system
	Appraised TSSA directives for gas systems to conform with CSA B149, O.Reg 212/01 & 214/01

EDUCATION

McMaster University Graduating in 2020	Bachelor of Engineering & Management Fourth year in a five year Civil Engineering & Management program crediting one year towards an MBA
	Current GPA of 11.9 on McMaster's 12 point scale (3.9 on 4 point scale)
Nanyang Tech University 2018	International Student Exchange Recipient of Travel Scholarship to study at NTU, an internationally renowned university for Civil Engineering

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- LEED Design: GA Certification acquired
- Structural Design and Analysis: SAP 2000, Revit
- Drafting and 3D Modeling: AutoCAD, Revit, Rhino (with V-Ray), 3DS Max
- Data Analysis: Matlab, MS Excel, Minitab
- Programming/Code: Python, Javascript, HTML, CSS
- Surveying: Use of Total Stations and Matlab for plotting/analysis
- Photo, Video, Document Editing: Photoshop, Sony Vegas, Acrobat, MS Office Suite

DAVID MOORE 2/2

RECENT PROJECTS

Beach House Design in the Philippines

2018

Independently designed a cost effective beach house available to villagers and tourists in Toledo,
 Philippines. Visiting the community allowed me to design with vernacular architecture in mind. Revit model, CAD drawings and photos of the structure are available at unmoore.com/portfolio

3D Design of Portable House

2018

Structural and Architectural design and video game walkthrough of a conceptualized portable home
with SIP walls and roof. Designed in Revit and imported to 3DS Max Interactive for game-like
walkthrough. Download and video available at unmoore.com/portfolio

Seismic Design Competition

2019

 As the leader of the architectural team I produced the final rendering of the structure using Rhino with V-ray and paneling tools for the facade. Render available at unmoore.com/portfolio

Timber Fever Competition

2018

• Designed and built a wooden structure with a team of architects and engineers that was displayed at David Pecaut Square in downtown Toronto. Photos available at unmoore.com/portfolio

Hackathons 2016, 2017

- First at McGill RoboHacks 2016 competition for creating a gesture-controlled model car: devpost.com/software/forceplay-l3jaq9
- Nominated Best Hardware Project at HackHarvard 2017 for interactive projection: devpost.com/software/blackbox-o3cazf

AWARDS

- Ontario Professional Engineer Scholarship: \$1500 acknowledging leaders in engineering affairs
- The Hatch Academic Grant in Engineering: \$2000 awarded for a high sessional average of 11.9
- Ronald William Merkel Engineering Scholarship: \$2500 recognizing international relief projects
- 2nd in McMaster Design Competition: Offered opportunity to attend OEC 2017
- University Prize for Special Achievement: Acknowledging my Philippines beach house project
- H.L. Hooker Scholarship: \$1500 awarded for attaining an 11.9 GPA
- Simon McNally Scholarship: Recognizing practical civil engineering experience and background
- McMaster Honour Award Scholarship: \$1000 value for a high school GPA of 94%
- Chemical Institute of Canada Award: For astounding scientific process in carcinogen research
- Gold Medal at Toronto Science Fair: Research on antioxidant effects on heterocyclic amines
- Offered Undergraduate Research Award at Ryerson to research High Performance Concrete

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

McMaster Civil Engineer Ambassador: Representing the Civil Department 2018 - Present Third Degree Black Belt: Instructor and Competition Judge 2010 - Present McMaster Steel Bridge Design Team: Analysed truss designs 2018 - Present McMaster EERI Seismic Design Team: Rendered skyscraper in Rhino with V-ray **2018 - Present** Concrete Toboggan Club: Concrete Design 2016 - Present Habitat For Humanity: Build Crew Member 2016 - Present NTU Dive Team: PADI Open Water Dive Certified 2018 Lane Attendant at Kennedy Bowl: Repaired pin-setting machines and assisted leagues 2013 - 2015McMaster Engineering Society: Student Member 2015 - Present High School Green Team: President & Event Coordinator 2015